# **JULIAN BUET**

SRE | DevOps Engineer

Email: julianbuet@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/julianbuet

I'm very passionate about resolving complex problems, learning and investigating new technologies. I like to help and learn alongside my team and dev colleagues to achieve our goals. Always happy to share knowledge and experience.

## Areas of Knowledge

- Working with AWS since 2017 and managing Kubernetes in production since 2018.
- Good knowledge in several languages (python, go, node, php...) to help developers debug microservices and solve integration problems.
- Strong experience in Infrastructure as Code with terraform and good knowledge configuring and maintaining observability tools.
- Security and cost reduction mindset.
- Design, management and ensurement of the reliability of a wide range of infrastructure systems.

## **Professional Experience**

### Job and Talent - Platform Engineer (Jan 2022 - Jun 2022)

- Administration and support of the AWS platform in production.
- Worked in the project of platform migration from AWS ECS to Kubernetes.
- Observability through Datadog, Cloudwatch and Rollbar.
- Automation and Infrastructure as code with Terraform, Ansible and Golang.

#### Dafiti - Technical Lead & Site Reliability Engineer (Jan 2021 - Dec 2021)

Responsible for the availability of ecommerce sites of 3 countries running in AWS.

- Technical leader of the SRE team (5 people)
- Upgraded and migration of old kubernetes clusters (version 1.7 to 1.21)
- Led the project to migrate the three main store apps to containers and Kubernetes.
- Implemented a new self-serve development platform with 50+ microservices using Okteto allowing Dev and QA teams to gain agility and helped reduce hours of troubleshooting.
- Designed the deployment workflow and architecture for the Kubernetes clusters.
- Developed a set of automation tools using Python (APIs/slack commands/lambdas).
- Migrated to a new CDN (from Akamai to Azion).
- Migrated to a new APM (from New Relic to Instana).

#### Banco del Sol - DevOps Engineer (Oct 2020 - Jan 2021)

- Responsible for maintaining and supporting a banking platform hosted in Azure.
- Administration, support and migration of Kubernetes cluster (AKS) in production.
- Observability through EFK and Prometheus.

#### Dafiti - Site Reliability Engineer (Oct 2019 - Oct 2020)

- AWS infrastructure region migration of 100 EC2 and 3 RDS and reduced 40% of costs.
- Implementation of new environments running in Kubernetes.
- Worked on designing the terraform code repository which takes care of the entire company infrastructure.
- Designed and migrated to a new network architecture for the production environment.

### Algeiba - Principal Technical Specialist (Jul 2017 - Oct 2019)

 Principal consultant managing several projects and clients. Responsible for the design, architecture and migration of banking and retail platforms. Technical leader of a technical infrastructure team (8 people).
Windows Servers, Exchange, Office365, Linux web servers, Azure.

### Zarcam - Technical Specialist (Jul 2015 - Jul 2017)

 System administrator of Windows and Linux Servers. Implemented and migrated web servers and mail servers.

## **Education & Certifications**

- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (2020)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate (2020)
- Azure Administrator Associate (2019) among other Microsoft certifications (MCSE)

## Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (Advanced/B2)